const questions = [
  
    {
        "numb": 51,
        "question": "Which of these complement factor is a marker of humoral rejection?",
        "answer": "C4d",
        "options": [
            "C3b",
            "C4d",
            "C5a",
            "C3d",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 52,
        "question": "A 45-year-old male complains of chronic joint pain, stiffness, and swelling, particularly in his hands and wrists. He reports that the symptoms worsen in the morning and improve with movement throughout the day. What autoimmune disorder is most likely causing his symptoms?",
        "answer": "Rheumatoid arthritis",
        "options": [
            "Multiple sclerosis",
            "Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)",
            "Rheumatoid arthritis",
            "Type 1 diabetes mellitus",
            "Hashimoto's thyroiditis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 53,
        "question": "Which of the following is secreted by classically activated macrophages (M1 )?",
        "answer": "IL-1 ",
        "options": [
            "IL-2",
            "NA",
            "IL-1 ",
            "IL-3",
            "IL-4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 54,
        "question": "Specific form of endocytosis involving the vesicular internalization of solid particles, such as bacteria. It is the process by w hich cells ingesl large objecls, such as cells which have undergone apoplosis, bacleria, or viruses. The function common to neutrophils. monocy;es, macrophages is",
        "answer": "Phagocytosis ",
        "options": [
            "Liberation of histamine ",
            "Destruction of old erythrocytes",
            "NA",
            "Immune response is reduced",
            "Phagocytosis "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 55,
        "question": "Which of the following cells is the main source of antigens for activation of the immune system?",
        "answer": " Macrophages\n",
        "options": [
            "Erythrocytes\n",
            " Neurons\n",
            "Fibroblasts",
            "Platelets\n",
            " Macrophages\n"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 56,
        "question": "Local lymph nodules are enlarged near the infected wound. Increased amount of macrophages, lymphocytes, lymphatic follicles in the cortical layer and large amount of plasma cells were revealed on histological examinat ion. What process in the lymphatic nodules represent these histological changes? ",
        "answer": "Antigen stimulation ",
        "options": [
            "Tumour transformation ",
            "Innate insufficiency of the lymphoid tissue",
            "NA",
            "Antigen stimulation ",
            "Acquired insufficiency of the lymphoid tissue "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 57,
        "question": "What is the process by which an individual becomes hypersensitive to a particular antigen upon initial exposure?",
        "answer": "Sensitization ",
        "options": [
            " Immunosuppression",
            "Immunization ",
            " Desensitization ",
            "Tolerance ",
            "Sensitization "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 58,
        "question": "A 45-year-old man presents with a history of seasonal exacerbations of asthma and allergic rhinitis. He reports worsening symptoms during the pollen season despite adherence to prescribed medications. Skin prick testing confirms sensitization to grass pollen. What lifestyle modification could help reduce his exposure to allergens and improve symptom control?",
        "answer": "Avoidance of outdoor activities during peak pollen times",
        "options": [
            "Smoking cessation",
            "Avoidance of outdoor activities during peak pollen times",
            "Consumption of a balanced diet",
            "Regular exercise regimen",
            "Use of air purifiers at home"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 59,
        "question": "Which of the following is a marker of T lymphocytes?",
        "answer": "CD8",
        "options": [
            "CD20",
            "CD19",
            "NA",
            "CD45",
            "CD8"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 60,
        "question": "Which of the following is a Type 2 Hypersensitivity reaction? ",
        "answer": "Mismatched blood transfusion ",
        "options": [
            "Arthus reaction ",
            "Mantoux test",
            "Chronic kidney rejection ",
            "Mismatched blood transfusion ",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 61,
        "question": "A 20-year-old woman with a history of asthma and allergies undergoes skin testing to identify potential allergens in her environment. A positive skin reaction to ragweed in this patient would be mediated by which of the following classes of immunoglobulin? ",
        "answer": "IgE",
        "options": [
            "lgG",
            "lgD",
            "IgE",
            "NA",
            "lgA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 62,
        "question": "Which of the following organs is not involved in acute graft versus host disease",
        "answer": "Lung",
        "options": [
            "Liver",
            "Lung",
            "Skin",
            "Git",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 63,
        "question": "A 52-year-old woman with a history of systemic hypertension and chronic renal failure undergoes kidney transplantation, but the graft fails to produce urine. A renal biopsy is diagnosed as \"hyperacute transplant rejection.\" Graft rejection in this patient is caused primarily by which of the following mediators of immunity and inflammation?",
        "answer": "Preformed antibodies",
        "options": [
            "Cyrotoxic T lymphocytes ",
            "Preformed antibodies",
            "Helper T lymphocytes ",
            "NA",
            "Mononuclear phagocytes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 64,
        "question": "Components of innate immunity are",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "Complement system factors",
            "All of the above",
            "Dendritic cells",
            "NK cells"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 65,
        "question": "A 5-month-old infant presents with recurrent fungal infections, particularly involving the skin, nails, and oral cavity. Laboratory tests show decreased levels of T lymphocytes. What primary immunodeficiency disorder is this patient likely suffering from?",
        "answer": "Severe combined immunodeficiency",
        "options": [
            "X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
            "Chronic granulomatous disease",
            "Severe combined immunodeficiency",
            "Hyper-IgM syndrome",
            "DiGeorge syndrome"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 66,
        "question": "Most common malignancy in AIDS:",
        "answer": "Kaposi sarcoma ",
        "options": [
            "Kaposi sarcoma ",
            "B cell lymphoma",
            "NA",
            "Leukemia of myeloid origin",
            "Burkitt's lymphoma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 67,
        "question": "A 31 -year-old man with AIDS complains of difficulty in swallowing. Examination of his oral cavity demonstrates whitish membranes covering much of his tongue and palate. Endoscopy also reveals several whitish, ulcerated lesions in the esophagus. These pathologic findings are fundamentally caused by loss of which of the following immune cells in this patient?",
        "answer": "Helper T lymphocytes ",
        "options": [
            "B lymphocytes",
            "Killer T lymphocytes",
            "Helper T lymphocytes ",
            "Monocytes/macrophages",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 68,
        "question": "Toll-like receptors, recognize bacterial products and stimulate immune response by",
        "answer": "Transcription of nuclear-factor-mediated by NFKB",
        "options": [
            "Perforin- and granzyme-mediated Apoptosis",
            "Cyclin",
            "Transcription of nuclear-factor-mediated by NFKB",
            "NA",
            "FADD ligand apoptosis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 69,
        "question": " In an inflammatory response, which of the following are involved in the recognition of the microbes or damaged cells?",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "options": [
            "Toll-like receptors",
            "All of the above",
            "Cytosolic receptor",
            "Mannose-binding lectin protein",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 70,
        "question": "A 45-year-old male complains of a burning sensation while urinating and increased urinary frequency. On examination, there is tenderness over the suprapubic area and dysuria. Urinalysis reveals leukocyte esterase and nitrites. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "answer": " Cystitis",
        "options": [
            " Cystitis",
            "Prostatitis",
            " Glomerulonephritis",
            "Pyelonephritis",
            " Nephrolithiasis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 71,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is false about transudate?",
        "answer": "It is caused by increased vascular permeability",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "It has a specific gravity of less than 1.012",
            "It is a protein-poor and cell-poor fluid",
            "It is a non-inflammatory edema or effusion",
            "It is caused by increased vascular permeability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 72,
        "question": "Rolling, adhesion, and transmigration occur by interactions between complementary adhesion molecules on leukocytes and endothelium. The expression of these adhesion molecules is enhanced by a mediator.  Which of these is not involved in this process?",
        "answer": "Produced only in sepsis",
        "options": [
            "Can have paracrine action",
            "Include interleukins ",
            "Cytokines are polypeptides",
            "NA",
            "Produced only in sepsis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 73,
        "question": "Which of the following statements does not apply to acute inflammation?",
        "answer": "Prominent cells involved are monocytes/macrophages and lymphocytes.",
        "options": [
            "Onset is rapid, occurring within minutes or hours.",
            "Tissue injury is usually mild and self-limited",
            "Prominent cells involved are monocytes/macrophages and lymphocytes.",
            "Local and systemic signs are prominent",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 74,
        "question": "Major components of acute inflammation are",
        "answer": "Emigration of leukocytes to site of injury",
        "options": [
            "Increased vascular permeability",
            "Vasodilation",
            "Emigration of leukocytes to site of injury",
            "NA",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 75,
        "question": "What is the of type of chronic inflammation?",
        "answer": "Granulomatous inflammation",
        "options": [
            "Fibrinous inflammation",
            "Purulent inflammation",
            "Granulomatous inflammation",
            "Serous inflammation",
            "Hemorrhagic inflammation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 76,
        "question": "A 14-year-old child, suffering from rheumatism, was admitted to the clinic with complaints of pain in the region of the heart, high fever, shortness of breath. On the 2nd day of hospitalization, death occurred from heart failure. Grossly: the heart is flabby, hypertrophied. Microscopically: edema, hyperemia, blood vessels are surrounded with lymphocytes, histiocytes. What type of inflammation in this case?",
        "answer": "Interstitial",
        "options": [
            "Fibrinous",
            "Granulomatous",
            "Serous",
            "Purulent",
            "Interstitial"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 77,
        "question": "The release of arachidonic acid from the membrane phospholipids is mediated mainly through the action of ",
        "answer": "Phospholipase A2",
        "options": [
            "Phospholipase A2",
            "Phospholipase A1",
            "Phospholipase C",
            "NA",
            "Phospholipase B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 78,
        "question": "A 30-year-old female presents with fever, chills, and fatigue for the past three days. She recently recovered from a urinary tract infection treated with antibiotics. On examination, her temperature is 38.8\u00b0C (101.8\u00b0F), and she has warm, flushed skin. What is the most likely cause of her fever?",
        "answer": "Endogenous pyrogens released from leukocytes during the infection",
        "options": [
            "Fever due to an allergic reaction",
            "Hypothalamic dysfunction secondary to antibiotic use",
            "Endogenous pyrogens released from leukocytes during the infection",
            "Pyrogens released from normal cellular metabolism",
            "Exogenous pyrogens produced by a viral infection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 79,
        "question": "Which type of bacterial toxin acts by stimulating the excessive release of cytokines?",
        "answer": "Superantigens",
        "options": [
            "Enterotoxins",
            "Exotoxins",
            "Endotoxins",
            "Neurotoxins",
            "Superantigens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 80,
        "question": "Which of the following bacterial virulence factors directly inhibits phagocytosis by preventing the fusion of lysosomes with phagosomes?",
        "answer": "Capsules",
        "options": [
            "Adhesins",
            "Endotoxins",
            "Leukocidins",
            "Exotoxins",
            "Capsules"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 81,
        "question": "In what cases can we notice processes such as hyperplasia and hypertrophy?",
        "answer": "Pregnant uterus",
        "options": [
            "Breast development in puberty",
            "Cardiac muscle in cardiomegaly",
            "Pregnant uterus",
            "NA",
            "Skeletal muscle in athelete"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 82,
        "question": "A 28-year-old woman experienced a decrease in the size of her immobilized leg after an injury. What term is used to refer to this pathology?",
        "answer": "Atrophy",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "lschemic necrosis",
            "Metaplasia",
            "Atrophy",
            "Hyperplasia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 83,
        "question": "Which organs lack permanent cells?",
        "answer": "smooth muscle",
        "options": [
            "Skeletal muscle",
            "Cardiac cells",
            "smooth muscle",
            "Neurons",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 84,
        "question": "A patient who died from a hemorrhagic insult. From the anamnesis: he had acute hepatitis 10 years ago. At autopsy, in addition to the changes characteristic of the basic disease, minimal changes in the liver were revealed. What is the recovery mechanism in this case?",
        "answer": "Regeneration of parenchymal cells",
        "options": [
            "Proliferation of connective tissue cells",
            "Regeneration of parenchymal cells",
            "Synthesis of extracellular matrix proteins",
            "Remodeling of connective tissue",
            "Scar formation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 85,
        "question": "Anaplasia is a hallmark feature of ",
        "answer": "Malignant tumors",
        "options": [
            "Normal cells",
            "Benign tumors",
            "Malignant tumors",
            "NA",
            "Both benign and malignant tumors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 86,
        "question": "All tumors with invasive properties metastasize(A). Reason (R): The invasive property of the tumor permits them to penetrate into blood vessels or lymphatics, thus allowing them to spread to distant sites. Which of the following statements is true? ",
        "answer": "A is false; B is true",
        "options": [
            "Both A and Rare true, but R is not the  Correct explanation of A",
            "A is false; B is true",
            "NA",
            "A is true; B is false",
            "Both A and R are true, and R is the Correct explanation of A."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "Increased risk of cancer is seen in which of the following? ",
        "answer": "Chronic ulcerative colitis ",
        "options": [
            "Chronic ulcerative colitis ",
            "NA",
            "Leiomyoma of the uterus",
            "Bronchial asthma ",
            "Fibroadenoma of breast "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 88,
        "question": "Which of the following is/are induced by LMP-1 gene plays a role in oncogenesis? 1. Human T cell leukemia virus type 1. 2. Hepatitis B Virus 3. Epstein Barr virus 4. Human Papilloma Virus ",
        "answer": "3on1y ",
        "options": [
            "NA",
            "1&4",
            "2&3 ",
            "3on1y ",
            "1 Only "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 89,
        "question": "What the name of benign tumor arising from columnar epithelium?",
        "answer": "Adenoma",
        "options": [
            "Osteoma",
            "Fibroma",
            "Adenoma",
            "Lipoma",
            "Papilloma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 90,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not true about adenomas?",
        "answer": "All adenomas form glandular Structures",
        "options": [
            "They are tumors arising from non-Glandular epithelial cells forming glandular structures",
            "They may or may not form glandular structures",
            "Benign epithelial neoplasm that are derived from glands.",
            "All adenomas form glandular Structures",
            "NA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 91,
        "question": "Which of the following is a disorganized but benign mass composed of cells indigenous to the involved site?",
        "answer": "Hamartoma",
        "options": [
            "Hamartoma",
            "Teratoma",
            "NA",
            "Choristoma",
            "Papilloma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 92,
        "question": "Microscopic examination of thyroid gland biopsy revealed changes in the structure of the gland: a well-differentiated epithelium of the glands with few mitoses and consist of groups of cells. Which type of adenoma occurs in this case",
        "answer": "Trabecular adenoma",
        "options": [
            "Tubular adenoma",
            "Cystadenoma",
            "Trabecular adenoma",
            " Fibroadenoma",
            "Acinar adenoma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 93,
        "question": "Which type of nevus often quite rich in melanin pigment",
        "answer": "Blue nevus.",
        "options": [
            "Intradermal nevus",
            "Juvenile nevus",
            "Compound nevus",
            "Blue nevus.",
            "Junctional nevus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 94,
        "question": "Not a characteristics of 'Dysplastic naevi' is",
        "answer": "measuring > 10 mm",
        "options": [
            "variegated pigmentation",
            "ill defined borders",
            "NA",
            "measuring > 10 mm",
            "undulating irregular surfaces"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 95,
        "question": "If anabolism is more than catabolism what would it be means?",
        "answer": "positive nitrogen balance",
        "options": [
            "increased protein breakdown",
            "negative nitrogen  balance",
            "decreased stabilized protein synthesis",
            "positive nitrogen balance",
            "decreased growth protein synthesis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 96,
        "question": "Loss proteins with urine (proteinuria) typically leads to which one of following types of edema?",
        "answer": "throughout body ",
        "options": [
            "abdominal cavity ",
            "pulmonary edema",
            "legs region",
            "throughout body ",
            "face region "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 97,
        "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic feature of obesity?",
        "answer": "Excessive accumulation of adipose tissue",
        "options": [
            "Excessive accumulation of adipose tissue",
            "Elevated levels of high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol",
            "Decreased appetite",
            "Increased risk of type 1 diabetes",
            "Low body fat percentage"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 98,
        "question": "Macrophages replete by exceeded cholesterol are converted to which one of these cells type?",
        "answer": "foam cells",
        "options": [
            "phagocytes",
            "APC",
            "foam cells",
            "immunocytes",
            "plasma cells"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 99,
        "question": "What symptom does not occur in diabetes mellitus?",
        "answer": "Weight gain",
        "options": [
            "Polyuria",
            "Weight gain",
            "",
            "Weight loss",
            "Polydipsia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 100,
        "question": "Which of the following is not found in diabetes",
        "answer": "Patients with type 2 diabetes are more prone to ketoacidosis as compared to type 1",
        "options": [
            "Patients with type 2 diabetes are more prone to ketoacidosis as compared to type 1",
            "Recognised endocrine causes of diabetes include acromegaly and cushing\u2019s syndrome",
            "NA",
            "The majority of type 2 diabetes mellitus patients die from cardiovascular disease",
            "Fasting blood sugar more than 126 establishes diagnosis of diabetes"
        ]
    }
];